So it was about four years ago, five years ago,
إذا فقد بدأت قبل أربعه أو خمسة سنوات مضت
I was sitting on a stage in Philadelphia, I think it was,
كنت أجلس في مسرح في فيلاديلفيا ، وأظن أنها كانت
with a bag similar to this.
مع حقيبة شبيهة لهذه
And I was pulling a molecule out of this bag.
وكنت أسحب هذا الجزئ من الحقيبة
And I was saying, you don't know this molecule really well,
لأقول أنتم لا تعرفون هذا الجزي جيداً
but your body knows it extremely well.
ولكن أجسادكم تعرفه جيداً جداً
And I was thinking that your body hated it, at the time,
وكنت أفكر أن أجسادكم كرهته في تلك الأيام
because we are very immune to this. This is called alpha-gal epitope.
لأننا متحصنين منه وهذا يسمى بأنزيم ألفا جال
And the fact that pig heart valves have lots of these on them
وفي الواقع إن صمامات قلوب الخنازير فيها الكثير من هذه
is the reason that you can't transplant a pig heart valve into a person easily.
هو السبب أن لا يمكنك زراعه صمام قلب خنزير بسهولة
Actually our body doesn't hate these.
في الحقيقة جسدنا لا يكره ذلك ولكنه يحب ذلك
Our body loves these. It eats them.
فجسدنا يحبها فهو يأكلها
I mean, the cells in our immune system are always hungry.
أقصد أن خلايا نظامنا المناعي دائما جائعة
And if an antibody is stuck to one of these things
وإذا تعود المضاد الحيوي على أحد تلك الأشياء
on the cell, it means "that's food."
في الخلية ، يعني هذا أن "ذلك غذاء"
Now, I was thinking about that and I said, you know, we've got this
الآن كنت أفكر في ذلك لأقول ، تعرفون أننا لدينا ذلك
immune response to this ridiculous molecule
رد مناعي لهذا الجزي التافه
that we don't make, and we see it a lot in other animals and stuff.
الذي لا نصنعه ، والذي نراه في كثير من الحيوانات والأشياء
But I said we can't get rid of it,
ولكنني قلت أنه لا يمكننا التخلص منها
because all the people who tried to transplant heart valves
لأن كل الناس الذين جربو زراعة صمامات القلب
found out you can't get rid of that immunity.
وجدوا أنهم لا يستطيعون التخلص من هذه المناعه
And I said, why don't you use that?
وقد قلت لماذا لا يمكننا إستخدام ذلك ؟
What if I could stick this molecule,
مذا لو وضعنا هذا الجزيء
slap it onto a bacteria
كشريحة داخل البكتريا
that was pathogenic to me, that had just invaded my lungs?
والتي كانت ضارة لي ، والتي دخلت عنوة لرئتي
I mean I could immediately tap into
أقصد أنه يمكنني فورا أن أطلب
an immune response that was already there,
رداً مناعي موجود هناك أصلاً
where it was not going to take five or six days to develop it --
في حين لن تنتظر خمسة أو ستة أيام حتى يتطور
it was going to immediately attack whatever this thing was on.
بل ستهاجم مباشرة أي شي بداخله
It was kind of like the same thing that happens when you,
أنه مشابه لماقد يحصل لك أذا ما
like when you're getting stopped for a traffic ticket in L.A.,
مثلاً وٌقفتم من أجل مخالفة مرورية في لوس أنجلوس
and the cop drops a bag of marijuana in the back of your car,
حيث يرمي الشرطي كيس المروانا في مؤخرة سيارتك
and then charges you for possession of marijuana.
ثم يتهمك بحيازتها
It's like this very fast, very efficient way to get people off the street.
أنها كذلك ، طريقة فعالة لأزالة الناس من الطريق
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
So you can take a bacteria
أذا يمكنك أن تأخذ بكتريا
that really doesn't make these things at all,
والتي لا تعمل تلك الأشياء أبداً
and if you could clamp these on it really well
وأذا تمكنت من شبك ذلك فيها جيداً
you have it taken off the street.
فأنت أزلتها من الطريق
And for certain bacteria
ومن أجل بكتيريا محدده
we don't have really efficient ways to do that anymore.
فأننا لا نملك حقاً أي طرق فعالة لفعل ذلك بعد الأن
Our antibiotics are running out.
مضاداتنا الحيوية بدأت تنفذ
And, I mean, the world apparently is running out too.
وأقصد أن العالم كما يبدو ينفذ كذلك
So probably it doesn't matter 50 years from now --
أذا أنه غالباً لايهم أذا كان بعد 50 سنة من الآن
streptococcus and stuff like that will be rampant --
فبكتيريا الستريبتكوس وأشياء أخرى ستكون عنيفة ،
because we won't be here. But if we are --
لأننا لن نكون هنا ، ولكن أذا بقينا ..
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
we're going to need something to do with the bacteria.
فإننا سنحتاج لفعل شيئ مع البكتريا
So I started working with this thing,
إذا بدأت بالعمل بهذا الشيئ
with a bunch of collaborators.
مع مجموعه من المتعاونين
And trying to attach this to things that were
نحاول أن نربط هذه الأشياء التي كانت
themselves attached to certain specific target zones,
نفسها مرتبطة بمناطق مستهدفة معينة
bacteria that we don't like.
البكتريا التي لا نريد
And I feel now like George Bush.
وأحس الآن كجورج بوش
It's like "mission accomplished."
أنه مثل "المهمة أنٌجزت"
So I might be doing something dumb, just like he was doing at the time.
أذا لعلي أعمل شي غبياً ، كالذي كان يفعله في ذلك الوقت
But basically what I was talking about there we've now gotten to work.
ولكن ببساطة ماكنت أتكلم عنه هناك أنه يجب أن نعمل
And it's killing bacteria. It's eating them.
وهي ستقتل البكتريا ، أنها تأكلهم
This thing can be stuck, like that little green triangle up there,
هذا الشي يمكن أن يبقى ، كذلك المثلث الأخضر في الأعلى
sort of symbolizing this right now.
أحاول أن أكون مجازي الآن
You can stick this to something called a DNA aptamer.
يمكنك أن يتدمج هذا في شي أسمه غلاف الحمض النووي
And that DNA aptamer will attach specifically
وهذا الغلاف للحمض النووي سيرتبط بالتحديد
to a target that you have selected for it.
بهدف قد أخترته له
So you can find a little feature on a bacterium that you don't like,
ليوجد خاصية صغيرة على البتكريا التي لا تريدها
like Staphylococcus -- I don't like it in particular,
مثل ستيفيلوككس ، والتي لا أحبها على وجه الخصوص
because it killed a professor friend of mine last year.
لانها قتلت بروفسور صديقي في العام الماضي
It doesn't respond to antibiotics. So I don't like it.
أنها لا تتجاوب مع المضادات الحيوية ، لذا لا أحبها
And I'm making an aptamer that will have this attached to it.
وأنا أصنع غلاف يحتوي على هذه مدمجة به
That will know how to find Staph when it's in your body,
والتي ستعرف كيف تجد بكتريا ستاف أينما وجدت في جسدكم
and will alert your immune system to go after it.
لتخطر جهازكم المناعي ليتخلص منها
Here's what happened. See that line on the very top
هذا ما حدث ، ترون ذلك الخط في اقصى الأعلى
with the little dots?
والذي فيه نقط صغيرة؟
That's a bunch of mice that had been poisoned
هذه المجموعه من الفئران التي تسممت
by our scientist friends down in Texas,
من صديقنا العالم هناك في تكساس
at Brooks Air Base, with anthrax.
في قاعدة بروكس الجوية ، بالأنثراكس
And they had also been treated with a drug that we made
وقد تم علاجهم بدواء قمنا بتصنيعه
that would attack anthrax in particular,
والذي يهاجم الأنثراكس بالتحديد
and direct your immune system to it.
ليوجه نظامكم المناعي لها
You'll notice they all lived, the ones on the top line --
تلاحظون أن جميعهم عاشوا ، أولئك في الخط الأعلى
that's a 100 percent survival rate.
ذلك بنسبه 100% معدل نجاة
And they actually lived another 14 days,
وقد عاشوا في الواقع 14 يوماً
or 28 when we finally killed them,
أو 28 إلى أن قررنا أن نقتلهم
and took them apart and figured out what went wrong.
لنشرحهم ونكتشف ما الذي حدث بشكل خاطئ
Why did they not die?
لماذا لم يموتوا؟
And they didn't die because they didn't have anthrax anymore.
لم يموتو لأنه لم يعد لديهم أنثراكس بعد الأن
So we did it. Okay?
أذا فقد فلعناها .. حسناً.؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Mission accomplished!
المهمة أٌنجزت